op--
人を忘れた　我が身が憎い
貴様ら　無事ここから帰れると思うな
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
I hate myself for no longer being human!
You will not leave this place alive.
Mugai...
無涯　蟲狩のリーダーってのはどういう意味だ
What does he mean you were
leader of the Insect Hunters?
Did you...
お前が　お袋を殺したのか
kill my mother?!
【黒揚羽降臨】
Kuroageha Arrives
Did you kill her?!
お前が殺したのか
This is great...
おもしれぇ　仲間割れかよ
Fighting each other?
Well, he did once lead the Insect Hunters.
さすが蟲狩の元リーダー
You two have fun.
せいぜい仲間同士で戦ってな
I have something to do...
俺にはやることがある　あばよ
Bye!
Why?
なぜだ　一体これはどういうことだ
What is this?
Instead of the Insect Hunters who are hunting me,
わらわを狙う蟲狩よりも
I can only think of this Tsukishima.
先程よりこの月島というもののことをばかり考えさせられている
お付きの方　ここは自分が
Miss, I will handle this!
そうか　なるほど
Oh... I understand.
この月島というものは
This Tsukishima...
わらわは月島と距離を取って蟲狩と対峙した
When I fought the Insect Hunters,
I moved away from him.
わらわの毒は敵味方の区別なく　死に至らしめてしまう故
My poison brings death to any it touches,
be they friend or foe.
それを知ってか
He must realize this,
この者は毒を出そうとすると　悉く邪魔をした
and so he interfered whenever
I tried to use my poison.
そして何より　この者は敵から一切の攻撃を受けていない
And above all, the enemy hasn't hurt him.
あの時のことも　このための布石
And it explains what happened back then.
そう考えれば　すべて合点が行く
I'm sure of it.
間違いない　この月島というものは
This Tsukishima must be a spy,
味方と偽り　わらわの能力を封じるための　蟲狩の仲間
sent by the Insect Hunters to prevent
me from using my power.
月島　一つ聞くが
Tsukishima, I need to ask you something.
Are you with the Insect Hunters...
おぬしは本当は蟲狩の…
邪魔だ　ハムシ
You're in the way, insect.
あの月島というものは　おぬしらの仲間ではないのか
Tsukishima isn't one of you?
何を言っていやがる
What are you talking about?
Stop moving around!
ちょこぼこと
月島流　富嶽返
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Counter!
Run away while there's still time, miss.
さぁ　今のうちにお逃げください　お付きの方
そして　蟲奉行様にお伝えください
And tell the Insect Magistrate that, together,
必ず一緒に江戸の空を見上げましょうっと
we can look at the sky in Edo!
ハムシがうるさくて敵わん
That insect is irritating me.
Understood.
承知
Hey, kid.
よー　小僧
Take this!
食らえ　刺針剣
Stabbing Needle Blade!
は　早すぎる
He's too fast...
わっぱ　次に生まれた時は
In your next life, choose a better occupation.
丁寧に生きろよ
煉獄槍
Purgatory's Spear!
お　お付きの方　ここは自分が
M-Miss...
I'll hold them off here...
月島
Tsukishima!
Mugai, you aren't playing fair.
無涯　あんたずりぃよ
そんなことされたら　切れるわけねぇだろう
If you do that, I can't kill you.
あんたがお袋を殺したわけじゃないのは分かった
I know you didn't kill my mother.
However, as former leader of the Insect Hunters,
だが　蟲狩の元リーダーさんよ　やったのは誰だ
you can tell me it was.
今それを知らねばならぬ時ではない
This is not the time for that.
You really aren't fair at all...
やっぱずりぃなぁ　無涯
行くぞ
Let's go.
Come on... Wait!
おいおい　ちょっと待てよ
本当にこの者はお前たちの仲間ではないのか
He really is not one of you?
知るか　そんな小僧
I've never seen the kid before.
そうか
I see...
蟲狩　わらわに少し時間をくれぬか
Insect Hunters, would you give me some time?
何を寝ぼけたことを言ってやがる
What? Hell, no!
下がれ
Stay back.
Hey, leader... What are you doing?
おいおいリーダー何やってんだよ
いや　この方が都合がいいかもしれん
Right now, this may be
the smarter course of action.
What was I thinking?
わらわはなんということを考えてしまったのだ
足りぬ力で
He merely wished to protect me,
それでもなお精一杯　勤めを果たそうとしただけなのに
using the little power he had...
なのになぜ わらわはこの者を一瞬でも疑ってしまったのだ
So why did I doubt him, even for a single moment?
なぜわらわはあの言葉を信じられなかったのだ
Why could I not believe his words?
すまぬ　月島
I'm sorry, Tsukishima...
わらわは遥か昔に　人を捨てたのだ
I stopped being human long ago.
この身は直に触れるものを　悉く毒によって殺してしまう
My poison kills anyone who makes
direct contact with my body.
人がわらわを蟲奉行などと祭り上げたのも　それゆえ
That is why they gave me the
position of Insect Magistrate.
わらわを恐れ　嫌い　挙句利用している
They fear me... They hate me.
And in the end, they try to use me.
人の心は策略と思うのが　骨の髄まで染み込んでしまっていた
I convinced myself
that all they did or said were
attempts to manipulate me.
人のぬくもりなど　ずっと忘れていた
A long, long time ago, I abandoned human warmth.
熱を失い　心の底まで冷たくなっていた
And without that warmth,  my heart froze.
今はなぜこの者のことばかり考えていたのか分かる
Now I understand why I couldn't
stop thinking about him.
わらわは純粋にこの者を傷つけたくないと思っていただけ
I simply didn't want to hurt him...
この者はさぞかし暖かかったのであろうな
He must have been so very warm.
I hate myself for no longer being human!
人を忘れた我が身が憎い
貴様ら　無事ここかれ帰れると思うなよ
You will not leave this place alive.
This cloth keeps out the poison
that leaks from my body.
これはわらわの体から毒が滲み出てくるのを防いでくれる布
今は逆にお前を守ってくれるであろう
Now, it will protect you instead.
戯言はやめろ
Enough talk!
Show yourself for what you are, Kuroageha!
早く正体を現せ　黒揚羽
Kuroageha...
黒揚羽
貴様らの五分にも満たぬその魂
I will take your puny souls...
わらわがちりあくたに潰してくれよう
and crush them into dust.
来るぞ
Here it comes!
これが　あの野郎の力か
Is that her power?
刺針剣　神速
Stabbing Needle Blade: High Speed!
It melted!
溶けた
This monster is immortal.
この化け物は不死
She was playing with us, like we were kittens.
先までは子猫とじゃれ合う程度だったのさ
そこまで分かっているならば
If you understand that much,
then prepare for your destruction.
さっさと朽ちるがよい
Kaina... Gaikotsu!
戒汝　蓋骨　頼むぜ
Do it.
「滅蟲邪刀ムシカリ」　照準よし
Evil Insect-Slaying Blade, Insect Hunter,
ready to fire.
撃て　戒汝
Fire, Kaina!
無駄なこと
It's useless.
わらわにはあらゆる攻撃が効かぬ
No attack can touch me.
そのような子供だまし　わらわが食らうと思うたか
Did you think that little trick would work on me?
先端の刃だけ残っている
The front blade made it through intact?
What is this?
何だ　これは…
What's going on?
どういうことだ　力が出ぬ
My power is fading...
The tiny red blade that pierced your chest
貴様の胸を撃った赤き小さな刃
名は「滅蟲邪刀ムシカリ」
was the Evil Insect-Slaying Blade, Insect Hunter.
どうだ　蟲奉行
Well, Insect Magistrate?
我らの憎しみを込めた刃の味は
Could you feel our hate
emanating from that blade?
その小さき刃「ムシカリ」は
That tiny blade, Insect Hunter,
元は身の丈一丈四尺の大業物の成れの果てだ
is what is left of a blade
nearly twelve feet long.
幾度も溶かし鍛えなおし
We melted and reforged it over and over,
670種の蟲の外骨格を練りこみ極限にまで力を極めた刃よ
mixing it with skeletons of 670 insect types,
increasing its power to the limits of possibility.
我らが鍛え始めて幾星霜　血反吐を吐き
It's been a very long time
since we began forging it,
and it has cost much blood and pain
before it was finished.
幾千と試行錯誤して　ようやく完成させたもの
その大業物とは我が一族に伝わる憎しみの大太刀
The giant sword it was forged from
symbolizes the hatred that runs
through our clan, the Jingaitou.
塵外刀よ
塵　塵外刀
J-Jingaitou?
そうだ
That's right.
それを貴様に打ち込んだことによって　貴様の中の蟲の力を殺し続ける
And by impaling you with it,
we can continually kill the
insect power within you.
つまり　貴様は無力なただのガキに成り下がったのだ
In other words, you're no more
than a helpless child now.
まさか　わらわの力を封じる手立てがあろうとは…
I never knew there was any
way to seal away my power.
日本を守るためのわらわの使命も…
My task of defending Japan has failed...
泡と化してしまった
Now, Insect Magistrate...
さぁ　蟲奉行　貴様はどうやって殺されたい
How shall we kill you?
Tsukishima?
月島
生きているのか
He's alive?
あれだけの攻撃を受けたというのに
Even after all those attacks?
ならばわらわは
Then I must get away...
遠くへ　月島の元より遠くへ
Far away from him!
No! I don't want to die yet!
嫌だ　わらわはまだ死にとうない
今更見苦しいんだよ
It's too late for that.
がっかりさせんじゃねぇぞ
Don't disappoint me.
嫌だ　放せ
No! Release me!
これでいい　こやつらの注意はわらわへ向かう
This is good...
Now they'll focus on me, not on him.
月島　どうか無事で生き延びてくれ
Tsukishima, please survive!
おい　このお侍　まだ生きてるぜ
Hey, this samurai's still alive.
What a pain in the ass.
マジうぜぇな
No! Stay away from him!
やめよ　その者に近付くな
そうか
I see...
そんなにこのハムシが大事なのか
This little insect matters that much to you.
Then I'll chop him into pieces
ならば貴様より先に 細切れにしてやろう
before I kill you.
や　やめよ
D-Don't...
蟲奉行　守るべき者ができた不幸をよーく味わえよ
Magistrate, you will now learn
how unfortunate it is,
having something to protect.
や　やめてくれ
S-Stop it!
無涯
Mugai!
間に合ったか
I made it in time.
無事か　蟲奉行
Are you all right, Magistrate?
うむ　だがわらわのために　この月島という者が…
Yes.
But this Tsukishima
sacrificed himself for me.
Well done,
よくやった　芋坊主
yam-boy!
貴様　また俺達の邪魔をしやがった
You've stopped us again!
You traitor!
この裏切者が
ぶっ殺す
I'll kill you!
Hurry! Get out of here!
早く　ここから逃げろ
逃げろと言われても
But I cannot run...
Nope.
無理だな　てめぇはここで死ぬ
You're going to die here—
松ノ原
Matsunohara!
市中見廻り組か
The City Patrol?
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
Roll them up!
ぐるぐる押さえ込み
全力引っ張り
Full-Power Pull!
Hell, no.
ふざけんな
甲脚
Armor Kick!
懺斬り
Repentance Slash.
行ってくれ
Get going...
俺は蟲狩と一戦しなきゃ気がすまねぇ
I won't be satisfied unless I get
to fight the Insect Hunters.
分かった
Got it!
Wait...
待ちやがれ
I won't let you escape!
行かせるか
Nor will we.
そりゃこっちのセリフだね
てめぇは今ここで死ぬんだよ
You're going to die here.
待ちな
Hold it!
黒蜘蛛組の頭　恋川左之助の女房 お菊を殺したのはどいつだ
Which one of you killed Okiku,
the wife of Koikawa Sanosuke,
leader of the Black Spiders?
You... Who are you?
お前　誰？
A fool who wishes to speed
his journey into hell?
地獄行きを願う愚か者か
黒蜘蛛組？
The Black Spiders?
あ～あの時の女か
Ah, that woman back then...
You guys, go on ahead.
お前ら　先に行け
こいつは俺に用があるらしい
It seems I should speak to him.
Does that mean...
ってことは
そうさ
Yes.
俺があの女を殺したのよ
I killed that woman.
邪魔者を消す巻き添えって感じだったけどな
When I was removing people in
our way, she got caught up in it.
そうか　お前か
Really...
So it was you?
Looks like it's time to drop
the "Killer of 99" name.
九十九斬りの二つ名　とうとう返上する日が来たぜ
Time out!
たんま
三刀流か
Three-sword style?
No matter how many,
何本あろうが　骨節鎌の敵ではない
they are no match for my jointed sword.
Here I go.
行くぞ
Jointed Sword: Beautiful Flower!
骨節鎌　カレンカ
Repentance Sword: Playback!
懺斬り　プレーバック
Now I am the Killer of 100.
九十九斬り　改め百人斬り
Insect Magistrate, I'm so glad you're safe.
蟲奉行様　ご無事で何よりです
It's been a long time, Matsunohara.
久しいな　松ノ原
I guess we cut it close...
危ないところだったようですね
Yes.
うむ　詳しいことは後で話すが
I shall give you the details later,
but at the moment, I cannot use my power.
わらわは今　能力がまったく使えん
そのつもりでいてくれ
Bear that in mind.
Yes, ma'am.
はっ！
I still can't believe that she's the Insect Magistrate.
この人が蟲奉行だなんて　まだ信じられない
What a pretty girl.
綺麗な女の子だな
By the way, is Tsukishima one of your men?
ところでこの月島という者は…
お前の部下か
Did Jinbei-kun do something rude?
仁兵衛君が何か粗相を
でかした　よくぞこの者をわらわの元へ送り届けてくれた
You did well, sending him to me.
I found you!
見つけた
Insect Magistrate, I'll kill you!
蟲奉行　殺す
大鯰槌
Earthquake Hammer!
松ノ原
Matsunohara!
Insect Magistrate!
蟲奉行様
なんてバカ力なの
What enormous power...
山を砕いちゃうなんて
He shattered a mountain!
Tenma!
天間
Please escape on your own, Magistrate!
お一人で逃げてください　蟲奉行様
い　いやじゃ
I will not.
This time, it is my turn.
今度はわらわの番なのじゃ
I will not run away alone...
一人では逃げぬ
行くぞ　月島
Let's go, Tsukishima!
We shall return to Edo together,
一緒に江戸に帰ろうぞ
Tsukishima.
月島
Tsukishima!
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
Next Time
次回　蟲奉行
Jinbei's Power Awakens.
目覚めた力　仁兵衛覚醒
I can see it... I can see it!
見　見えるぞ
Koikawa-dono's three-sword style and Mugai-dono's swordsmanship.
恋川殿の懺撃も
無涯殿の太刀筋も
Hibachi-dono, you got new underwear.
火鉢殿　ふんどしを新調しましたね
Stay down!
Jinbei's Power Awakens!!
このまま寝てろ
「目覚めた力　仁兵衛、覚醒！！」